So we're updating the dashboard, right,
to be more, more reusable basically,
right.
And so we are creating recalling on
widgets,
which are like small customizable
elements that you can drag in.
So it will look basically like this.
So you can pick which ones are being
displayed like you have, like,
like your normal sidebar and everything.
But in here,
you can pick and choose what you want to
be displayed, right.
And we can currently already do that.
Yeah, you can.
You can pick one at a time,
but you could technically have multiple
in the new design if you wanted.
OK,
so instead of being limited to just two,
one on top, one on bottom,
you can actually add more than that.
That's what you're saying.
Yeah, exactly.
And so I'm looking at updating this
payroll schedule time off and the design
I came up with is this one here.
It's going to look a bit messy or a bit
noisy because I still have to refine it a
bit more.
But imagine where you have the employee,
the employee name and you click down to
see the information in here,
you would have kind of the employee's
name and the dates.
So it's the 12th to the 14th consolidated
to 1.
So the first question is, do you need,
do we still need to bring probably do to
bring in for each date as in not each
request, but each day of the request?
Does that make sense?
So like if I'm going here, it's a first,
a second, a fourth,
or does that make sense?
Yeah.
Like is it OK, I'm gonna go look and see.
Oh, no, sorry.
OK,
so they put it at a start and the end
date.
I'm just going through this real quick
just to kind of see the various ways.
All right, So that can gets.
Like, yeah.
And I'm,
I'm just looking at how it looks like
it's doing it by day.
It's not doing it like a yeah,
here's a date range.
Yes, I think,
I think just to be consistent with the
payroll module itself,
you'd want to show one row per day and
not do date ranges.
I know in real life it makes a lot more
sense to do a date range if they're
taking a whole week off or three days in
a row off.
But I think just to keep it consistent
with the way it looks in the payroll
module you might have,
we might have to go back and display,
you know, one row per day.
And then with this,
we had a talk with let me get his name.
I don't want to get wrong.
I think it's Ben Lane or Yep, Ben Lane.
Yeah,
he was saying pay groups would be better
the group by the department,
but his department ever used or would it
just better that default interest to pay
group?
This was his feedback by the way.
Promise.
Well,
I know that the the time off approval is
based on home department.
OK,
so the way you assign a supervisor over
certain employees is handled by the home
department.
So the pay group is just based on the pay
group that's assigned to their
compensations.
Yeah.
And what makes it a little bit messy is
that it would be possible to have one
employee that's being paid compensations
and multiple pay groups.
So using pay group as a filter would
would not be as good as far as show me
who you know, like in your case,
Marcus Bell, Right.
Like I'm only seeing it.
I don't know.
The home department to me is better
because each employee can only belong in
one home department,
whereas an employee could have belong in
10 different pay groups.
So I I'm sure,
I'm sure Ben's pulling on some real world
knowledge there and the fact that a lot
of clients out-of-the-box don't use home
departments, but they all use pay groups.
So it might be more common to someone
who's new,
but it's but the fact that we actually
assign the security, if you will,
as far as the ability to for someone to
approve the time off request,
that's all based on department.
I would kind of lean forward to the
department side,
but then is our value on keeping the
option to change the view on to whichever
1 you want or what's your,
what would be your thinking on this?
Well, yeah.
And the time off request, of course,
is also not specific to a pay group.
You're just simply looking at their
current compensations and seeing what
their pay group is and then they're using
as an employee filter.
Right, Exactly.
Yeah.
And then as far as the compensations they
actually have,
you have to go down to the detail level
to see what the starting date is to make
sure we're not pulling a pay group that
they belong to 20 years ago,
that they're no longer in, right.
So we're we're pulling in just their
current active pay groups.
So that that should be something else
just to make sure.
Yeah, yeah.
It's like,
it's like in the and I don't have the the
tables right in front of me in sequel,
but I know on the header level is where
you see if it's active or inactive.
So you'd have to check that.
And then at the detail level is where you
would see the actual date.
So if the same compensation is listed,
you know,
the up to detail Level 3 or 4 times,
you want to grab the most recent date,
or at least the date that that makes
sense based on the system clock,
which today is August 10th.
So as long as you're doing all that cool
stuff, then I think pay group is fine.
We can go and we can go and let it,
let it let that go,
especially if Ben recommended that.
You know, Ben's kind of like me.
He's been around a long time,
so he knows this stuff really well.
Maybe,
maybe we could have it always default to
department 1st and just have pay group as
an option.
Yeah, or something that's totally fine.
Like like that stuff is easily changed
because again this is in the concepts
phase,
not a built out anything department as
default.
OK.
Next question then would be kind of on
the calendar.
And I know this looks messy because it is
and right now we don't have any calendar
at all, right?
Is this something that would be brand new,
OK, This would be new OK,
because because we're revamping and kind
of enhancing what was there originally.
Again,
this is messy because it should fit on
one screen, but as you can see it doesn't.
So then the we have these different types,
the vacation sick personal on the on the
where is it under compensation?
It's under this was got from employees
paid.
Yeah, it's a yeah.
Employer is where you'd actually set up
which ones you want to use,
what you want to call them.
Yeah, kind of thing.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah.
And so just certain ones are under like
sick and holiday.
I was going to keep this one possibly up,
I'm not quite sure because it's kind of
hard to know if it's going to be in which
one.
But anyway,
is it in your mind valuable to give the
different icons for different reasons or
no?
Well, The thing is, is that again,
a user could make the first one be sick
and not vacation so.
So in that case you'd be showing the cool
umbrella for sick instead of the vacation
time.
So again,
that what you put down were the default
descriptions, your vacation, sick,
personal, miscellaneous.
But the next client might have those
completely reordered or call them
something totally different that might
not match the the cool icon.
So true.
True.
Yeah.
Because they can configure it any way
they want or can.
No, it's never fixed.
Let me check something.
Actually, Yeah,
if you go to modify employer.
Yeah.
And then time off hours,
the last tab up there.
Yeah.
So they can actually rename the short
long description to whatever they wanna
use.
And they and those checkboxes dictate if
they even want them to show at all or not.
The ones that they're.
Yeah, those active checkboxes.
So in this case.
But then what about these ones here
though,
that just means if if they are choosing
to accrue time off hours,
meaning if you work, in other words,
you accrue .
1 time off hours per hour of work or
something.
And not everybody does that.
But if they do that,
what types of pay will make that happen
is what those check boxes are doing right
down there.
So that that would basically those check
boxes below would not affect your
calendar whatsoever.
Your calendar would only care about the,
you know, those top 4 fields.
OK,
so I need to scrap that then
realistically,
because this is not going to work.
But that's OK, I think.
I think even just showing them as
different colors is definitely fine.
Also the different colors right now would
be this is approved by whoever approves
this.
This would be pending and then this would
be again.
Then on rejection is rejection.
Let me check again under how to do this
again.
Are we going to employee?
Yeah, I guess it's an employee,
but how do you confirm again,
someone's time off and they could either
do it on the employee record or they
would use the widget to say yes,
I approve it.
They could actually technically do it in
the portal too.
That's I guess three locations they could
approve it and then here, right, Yes,
exactly.
So the question is there's no rejection.
So what happens then with like
something's not approved and the date
goes past?
What would be the expectation there?
Kind of that's a good question.
Like could they approve it later on what
they get to pay later or how does that
work?
Like makes sense.
You're right,
because pretty much they either just
approve it or just don't do anything with
it.
Yeah.
And it's kind of interesting.
I never,
I never thought about that before.
It's one of those things where you're
saying it, I'm like, well, you know,
it makes perfect sense.
So like in in my mind, don't get me wrong,
I'm not an expert in any of this,
but if the date had passed and it hadn't
been accepted, would it just like, OK,
rejected is the wrong word,
but like outstanding maybe would be a
better word for us.
Yeah, we could.
We could probably make up a word because
you're right,
because pretty much everything is one of
two statuses.
It's either pending or it's approved.
We really don't have a third status.
Like in purchasing management,
your request can be approved or rejected
and and there's,
there's multiple organs to be open so
it's easier to do something like that.
But yeah, the time off,
I guess like you said,
if it's outstanding and the dates in the
past, yeah, I, I, we could make up a word.
I'd be OK with you all come with any word
you want to call it because it rejected
might be a little too strong, but I guess,
I guess you could just say unapproved.
I don't know if that's if that's too
similar to outstanding.
I don't know that that's I'd,
I'd be OK with the Ben or Fergal,
whoever wants to sit down,
come up with a good word for that.
As far as a date that's passed,
that was never approved.
And then this would be, again,
kind of new functionality.
Is it going to work for me?
It's not going to work for me.
Can I check here?
Is it working?
No, it's not.
Oh, sorry, it's here.
This then was another idea that I had.
Again, we're on the concept side of it.
Let me see.
I should have one person.
Yeah.
So another idea was you could click the
information and this is then how many say
days on vacation,
sick icons again will have to go away.
But as in whatever they've configured on
their side for the employee time off,
whatever is scheduled here on this one,
it would show all of them.
And how many days of the taken of these
would that be a good idea or a bad idea?
Yeah, that sounds good.
And because if someone had backed up a
lot of say vacation or sick days that it
would show here that the racking kind of
higher numbers and then this the down
below is people are also wanting to take
the same time off.
And so before you even approve,
you could see if there's any conflicts of
like, oh,
I need one of you 2 for my team to stay,
stay here or whatever.
You know,
I can't have both you off same time.
Yeah, that sounds good.
OK, perfect.
That's all I really had for you.
But if you're if you have free time for
me, I'd have one more question for you.
Sure, go for it.
So remittance,
let's make sure that I show what was
currently there.
Maybe I'm being stupid,
but is remittance from the start of year
to this date or is this from like this
date receipts true?
What exactly is this?
Like do you get what I'm saying?
As in like from when to when is this
going to be considered?
Because if I go back two years and I pick
a date, I have all these active.
What are they called again?
No, I'm still in payroll.
Yeah, I guess.
I guess if our doing say a query on the
database, I think I would, yeah,
take whatever date you're putting in the
date receipts through.
I think I would look for pledges with a
pledge date that happened like right
before that.
OK, so like in real life, Yeah,
real life it's always a calendar year
that someone programmatically can choose
something different they want to.
But in this case, if it's August 1, 2024,
I need to then go back until I find the
first begin date that happened before
August 1st, 2024,
which probably will be as far as the
pledge begin dates.
So it which would probably be January
1/20/24.
So I would then go ahead and,
and use that as my date range as far as
what's the display in the widget.
Either that or we could just say forget
it.
We're going to always assume it's a
calendar year and it's always,
if they choose 81,
we're always going to just assume it's
January 1 for the begin date.
So we, we could start off like that.
We could start off with just whatever
date they choose.
We're just assuming it's a calendar year.
We're always going to use a January 1 for
the begin date.
But if someone it's possible,
there's one really weird client out there
who's doing something funky with the with
this module that we were unaware of.
And they have different begin dates on
their pledges for some reason.
So,
so like what you would say then here you
could have kind of not today then,
but you could change it to kind of fiscal
year to date kind of thing.
Like,
and then you don't want to use the word
fiscal because that makes people think
about their general Ledger fiscal years.
And this has nothing to do with the
general Ledger fiscal year.
So you definitely want to,
it's definitely a pledge year to date
year or a calendar year to date.
Either that or you could just give them a
begin and an end date for the widget.
And that way they're just in full control
over it.
And that way we don't have to assume
anything or look at anything.
They just put in a begin and an end date
and we just go.
So that'd be an option.
It would be,
I'm trying to think then how would you do
everything down below that would work?
This would probably break though.
Would it break?
Technically, you get the amount expected.
Yeah, that could work.
And if they do something silly like they
put in July 1 to July 31, well,
there's no pledges in that range,
but there is some activity in that range.
So we can at least show them the activity.
So the percentage, you know,
the percentage paid and the pledge
amounts will be 0,
but we could at least show paid.
A column if they did something crazy like
that, the date range.
So,
but if they're date range actually
include a pledge, well,
then now we can actually display an
amount for the pledge column expected
column outstanding, a percent paid column.
So maybe that maybe that would be the
most flexible.
They could use this widget both for just
seeing activity in a time period,
or they can also use it for what you have
it set up to do.
Where is the show pledge,
how much they've given a pledge, balance,
all that good stuff.
So you're kind of talking about kind of
the unposted remittance.
Is that what you're trying to say?
Like you can show what hasn't been paid,
what has been pledged for that time,
or am I misunderstanding?
Yeah.
What?
Yeah.
Unposted just means that they've created
some remittances.
They just haven't posted it to the
database.
It's not it's not been finalized yet.
So yeah, I'm just saying for the wizard.
True, but it's expected, right?
No, they,
they typically wouldn't put it in here
unless they actually have received
something.
So it's more like a I'm in the process of
entering the remittances and I just,
I'm going to post them all together.
I'm just not done.
I'm not finished entering them all in yet.
So it's just kind of in a limbo state
until I actually post them.
OK.
But I'm trying to think right now that
because it yeah.
And right now that does just say date
receipts through yeah.
Because for me, honestly,
I am viewing in my mind this to be from
this date to current date,
what has been given to these activities.
I can't always just do this, can't I?
It looks like it looks like just assuming
a January 1 for a begin date is how it's
currently working.
Oh,
you think it's it's the start of the year.
So it's from this date to January 1st.
Yeah.
So it looks like that's how it's
currently working.
If we wanted to enhance it or make it
more flexible,
we could allow them to actually choose
the begin date.
But I think right now we choose date
receipt through 81.
It's just assuming A11 to 81 date range.
OK, I get it now.
I get it now how it's working.
So I mean, they should all disappear now.
They did not disappear.
So there.
But I mean, activity happened in OK,
I'm going to see if,
if you if you have enough patience,
I'm going to see what happens if you
don't have a pledge,
but you do have verbenets if it works or
not,
because I'll be or have you already
tested that or No,
I didn't test it in the normal sense.
Give me one second.
I.
That's fine.
Yeah, I'll, I'll do it real quick.
It won't take me about 60 seconds.
That's wrong.
One wrong, one wrong document.
Immense pledge legacy behavior because I
sent my agent to quickly check to see how
that was working.
But OK, taking up this now.
OK, I'm about to post it over here.
It's posted.
Let's try to go back.
OK, Yeah, OK, so forget what I said.
So it does look like the widget currently
is it's assuming and it's based on
pledges.
So it's not going to show anything at all
unless they pledge exists.
Once again,
I was just kind of thinking outside the
box and can we make it more useful where
it's not tied to a pledge,
it'll show anything.
So right now it looks like there's there
has to be a pledge.
The date range is assumed January 1
through whatever date you select and it's
looking at the pledges in that date range.
And then also it's showing you the
activity between January 1 and in this
case August 1st,
that once against the current
functionality,
it's up to you if you want to enhance or
give them extra bells and whistles or
something.
So all I did for my version of this was
to see for on pace before the end of the
year to reach your goal.
You also have them here,
the different activity,
because from my point of view,
this is just realistically active
activities.
So it's whatever I have in here,
the different activities and to see if
we'll reach that goal here.
That makes sense.
And so like all I was going to do was try
to see if we could like I will be in pace
to reach that call by the end of the year
or whatever activity because obviously
you can,
you can have it be whatever date you want
it to be these activities.
So if I go to the college fund,
for example,
I have a start date and an end date.
Yeah, it's not, It's not looking at that.
Yeah.
So it's actually looking at the pledge
dates.
So the pledge beginning end dates so that
those activity dates don't really do
anything.
No,
But would it not be the expectation to be
let me open the sign new screen because
maybe I'm misinterpreting kind of what
people use this for.
But isn't this time to see if the
activity will reach the goal,
but the goal is dictated by the pledges
made to the activity.
True, true.
That's case I'm wrong in OK, yes,
you you could ignore,
you can ignore the fact there's a certain
end date on the activity itself because
that doesn't really affect any of the
reporting.
It's more just there to look pretty just
information only.
So but yeah,
the widgets going to look at the
individual pledges.
They're set up under manage pledges.
And then the pledge dates would typically
start, you know,
January 1 to end of the year for each
individual church.
And then therefore,
the widget would only show remittance is
actually being given to those pledges in
order to show on the widget.
Yeah.
And so just to be clear,
then a pledge would be like,
I'm donating to €10 a month for the next
12 months.
And then the remittance would be, oh,
what's the definition of remittance again?
Just basically the money that you paid
against the pledge.
Yeah, OK, that means, OK,
I'm a little bit confused.
OK,
I've gone really far wrong in this and no,
it's fine.
So you're so basically you have to pull
like you know,
in our building that is a is a database
query.
I would start with the remit it's pledge
table and and then grab the date range
for those pledges first.
And then after I have that,
that least gives me the year to date
expected the, you know,
the annual amount you're there at the
beginning.
So at least I have all that information
upfront per activity.
And then from from that pledge,
I'll then link from that over to the
actual orbit.
It's history,
the populate the year to date paid and
then that can calculate all the other
stuff, you know,
the outstanding percent paid, all that,
all that kind of thing.
So, so the remittance history table,
you wouldn't be pulling straight from
that.
You would actually be pulling from the
pledge table 1st and then going from the
pledge table over probably I guess to the
remittance history detail table is
probably where it's hooked.
Yeah.
But like this, Yeah,
this one's gonna have both begin and end
date.
It's gonna have the activity ID in it.
OK, OK, OK.
I'm getting, I'm sorry, the pledge.
Yeah.
Pledge detail tables gonna have activity
in it.
Yeah.
So this is where I've gone wrong, right?
And I'll tell you exactly what I was
envisioning for this.
Yeah,
because you're pulling it based on the
dates, on the activity itself, which,
yeah, yes, kind of kind of bit more.
So I was kind of caring about the
activities as activities would be the
buckish, you could say, you know,
and this thing was just the amount that
God entered through the pledges.
But what actually matters is the
activities.
But what you're saying to me is I don't
actually care about the activities at all,
what I care about with the pledges.
And so actually this is just kind of it,
what money has gone into my activity.
But what you actually care about this
kind of a breakdown on what pledges are
outstanding or what pledges are behind
their timetable.
Is that correct in kind of what people
are trying to use this for more so the
way as far as visually what you're seeing
right now?
Yeah, that's correct.
I do want to see all this information
broken down by activity.
It's just that I have to start with the
pledge.
The pledge is what dictates which
activities display.
Yeah.
And then after I have the pledge,
then I can go look for it.
Can now show me the rabbits that's
actually connected to this pledge to get
the totals.
So would would this be better than right?
So let's say I click on this, right?
And then or let's say click on this.
So in this design,
I was thinking on just to see the amounts
coming in, but this is actually wrong.
I'm going the wrong direction here.
What I would expect is like,
let's say I drop down,
so I click and say outreach and and so
forth.
And inside you can see all the pledges
that are for the activity and then see if
they're outstanding or what's the status
with them.
That would probably be a better approach
to this, right?
It would, but a lot of our customers,
they may have 508 hundred pledges to one
of these activities.
So just kind of keep in mind visually,
if I click that and I have that many
pledges against activity,
what's it going to look like or how are
we going to, you know,
paginate or paginate, you know,
all that information or is that too much
data?
But that's exactly how I did though.
I would just basically limit to maybe the
top 20, let's say, or top ten maybe.
And then if they want more information
instead of what I'm being displayed here,
I can give a more detailed list or a way
of querying like who is the most
outstanding, who's in an active maybe?
Or do I mean kind of going more so to
find who's behind and maybe contact them
or reach out or whatever they normally do.
OK,
that was absolutely amazing because I
went the wrong direction.
So this is actually fixed my issue here.
It's all good.
Like I said,
it's it's it's confusing that you have
dates on the activity and you have dates
on the pledge and you have the dates for
the actual orbited centuries themselves.
So there's a lot of dates floating around
in those ribbon it's tables.
So it totally makes sense that you kind
of went the way you went.
OK, OK, perfect, perfect.
You've sorted out two huge issues and now
I know what I'm doing.
It's like in this, you can also,
once you create your widget,
you should be able to put it right beside
the current widget and kind of see that
the totals all match up and they're
correct and stuff.
Yeah.
And if you need better data in that beta
one environment or something, let me know.
And I can go add a couple of pledges for
2026 and put some abundance against them
and do some various things like that.
If someone if someone were QA ING this,
they would put in a pledge with no
abundance.
They'll put in for minutes against no
pledge and you would have a pledge with
her, but it's tied to the pledge.
And then you would so you have all the
different weird environments you could
think of and then go test the widget out
and see how it's handling that.
And again, to me,
it's like the the the widget is a pledge
widgets.
I start with the pledge and the oiler,
but it's I care about is there,
but it's actually hooked to that pledge.
I'm not going to actually show all rabbit.
It's in the date range.
It has to be hooked to the pledge.
Yeah, yeah.
Let me know if you need any, but any,
any other data or anything out there to
kind of help test it or something when
you get closer.
So at the moment we're thinking about
stealing the sales guys information.
OK, I forget what it's called.
That's not goodwill.
It's what's it called.
I can open it up and I can just see it
from there.
I don't know how good their data is.
I just know that they have a lot of it.
The Generations Church, OK,
because we have not to be able to already
remit.
It's might be one of those modules.
They don't have a lot of stuff in it just
because.
Yeah.
It's more of a denominational
headquarters type module.
It's not used as often or sold as often
as the standard modules that all churches
and almost all of our clients use.
So again, if you find, if you look at it,
there's really not a lot of data or not
enough data to do an adequate testing on
it, just let me know because I'm kidding.
We can add stuff to it.
OK, perfect.
I did not expect this to go so long,
but it absolutely was amazing help.
So thank you again.
Yeah, No sweat.
Anytime.
All right.
Appreciate it.
Bye, bye.
Sure.
Talk to you later.
Bye.